Terry Xu

Software Developer at Platypus Networks

terry@bneing.com

Summary

Possess specialized knowledge of software project management and have experience across the full system development life cycle. Know well most web technologies and have plenty of experience on web tools, like JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, Ajax, MySQL, PYTHON, Django. Adhere to deadlines and hard working.

Experience

Software Developer at Platypus Networks

November 2014 - Present

Platypus.net.au is a progressive company of IT professionals including Network Engineers, Software Programmers, Graphic Designers, Network Administrators and Architects. It specializes in providing end to end IT and Communication solutions for every industry in the SMB to Enterprise sectors and tailors IT Networks and Management for Increased Business Productivity.

Responsibilities:

Refactor obsolete VB ASP code to ASP.NET

Redesign layout and adopt JQuery UI, Ajax for better UI
Rewrite MS SOL stored procedure and views to speed up data retrieving

Use Bootstrap to design and program new modules

Find and fix bugs in old system quickly and effectively

Basically, my job in this company is maintaining and upgrading an internal website for a clinical system, it consists of numerous small projects, like a feedback panel for the patients, a staff movement tracking system, etc. The back-end mixes VB Script and VB.NET, and the front-end uses JQuery, JQuery UI, Bootstrap, and all knowledge about HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

In the beginning, my duty was refactoring the 10 years old clinical system into up-todate, user-friendly and new-designed interface, rewriting back-end codes to speed up, and consolidating stored-procedure and views for MS SQL.

After that, I did lots of upgrading work for that system, and almost all reports and charts.

I also coded the new responsive company website: http://www.platypus.net.au/.

Lead Developer at Bneing Technology

2011 - 2013 (3 years)

Implemented most functions and features from ground up.

Transferred from mock-up to code, involved cross-browser compatibility.

Developed responsible webpages for mobile platforms.

Worked with the founder/CEO and the technical leader to refine and add new features to the product

Managed and assisted other co-developers.

Education

Sydney Institute of Interpreting and Translating

Advanced Diploma of Translating, Language Interpretation and Translation, 2013 - 2013

The University of Queensland

Master's Degree, Information Technology, 2009 - 2011

Xidian University

Bachelor's Degree, Mechanical Engineering in Automation, 2004 - 2008

Terry Xu

Software Developer at Platypus Networks

terry@bneing.com



Contact Terry on LinkedIn